Guide to the William Coleman research files CBHM.0032
Center for Brooklyn History
- Series 1: Primary sources, 1698-1896
  - Sub-series 1.5: Oaksmith family, 1846-1896
    - Clippings, 1857-1870 (Box 2)
      "The African Slave Trade. Five New Slavers Under Way. Two Vessels Captured." Evening Post 59.293, December 14 1860.
      "City Religious Press." New York Evangelist, June 26 1862.
      "The Case of the People Against Mr. Woodford," "Greeley and Woodford," "New Evidence Against Gen. Woodford," "The Slave Trader Convicted to a Demonstration." Brooklyn Eagle, October 1870. (Stewart L. Woodford, scandal over escape of Oaksmith.)
    - Legal and government documents, 1851-1876 (Box 2, Box 3)
      Wm. Bourgoyne and John Plume vs. The Steam Ship Gold Hunter. United States District Court, San Francisco. August 18, 1851.
      United States v. Appleton Oaksmith, U.S. D.C. Mass (1861). Margaret Scott
      Bark Augusta--cargo seized and related documents. June 25, 1862.
      44-1-123. Connection of Hon. Robert C. Schenck with the Emma Mine and Machado Claim. February 25, 1876. (Vessels Thomas Watson & Mary Varney.)
    - Appleton Oaksmith, circa 1850s-1873 (Box 3)
      Appleton Oaksmith documents from East Carolina University, Special Collections Department, Joyner Library. circa 1850s-1880s.
      Brig Mary Adeline and Brig Camargo documents, 1851.
      Haitian shipping manifests, 1854.
      Appleton Oaksmith journal [held at Duke]. 1855.
      [Appleton Oaksmith writings], 1855-1874.
      Goicouria and Avezzano letters, 1856.
      Document regarding Oaksmith's appointment as a commissioner from NYC to the Southern states, 1861.
      Dispatches from the United States Consul in Havana relating to Appleton Oaksmith [from vertical files at Rosenberg Library, Galveston, TX], 1864.
      "Southern State Debts and the National Currency..." The Southern Magazine 8, 1873.
    - Elizabeth Oakes Smith, 1846-1896 (Box 3)
      Letters to and from John Neal and Mary Neal Sherwood, 1846-1856.
      May, Caroline. The American Female Poets: with biographical and critical notices. Philadelphia, PA: Lindsay & Blakiston, 1853.
      Scrapbook pages with clippings. 1869-1880
      Elizabeth Oakes Smith documents at New York Public Library. circa 1870s-1890s
      A Human Life, Being the Autobiography of Elizabeth Oakes Smith. circa 1885
      Cohen, Isabel E., compiler. Readings and Recitations for Jewish Homes and Schools. Philadelphia, PA: The Jewish Publication Society of America, 1896, pp. 118-120, "The Jewish Captive" by Elizabeth Oakes Smith.
    - Seba Smith, 1851-1872, 2019 (Box 3)
      Seba Smith-Jack Downing letter, 1851. [Coleman notes: "probably not real."]
      Camp, David N., ed. The American year book and national register for 1869… p. 796. Entry for Seba Smith.
      Griffin, Joseph, ed. History of the press of Maine, Bowdoin. 1872. pp. 54-55 re: The Courier, founded by Seba Smith.
      Seba Smith family tree, 2019.
    - Other documents, 1852-1883 (Box 3)
      [Naval correspondence], 1852-1853.
      The Appeal of the Religious Society of Friends in Pennsylvania, New Jersey, Delaware, etc., to their fellow-citizens of the United States on behalf of the Coloured Races. Philadelphia, PA: Friends' Book-store, 1858, pp. 18-21.
      The Great Republic Monthly, July 1859. New York, NY: Oaksmith & Co. [original magazine]
      Mix, Jacob. "The Biter Bit; or the Robert Macaire of Journalism. Being a Narrative of Some of the Black-mailing Operations of Charles A. Dana's 'Sun.'" Washington, DC: 1870, pp. 59-69.
      [Selections from magazine] Old Times in North Yarmouth, Maine. Yarmouth, ME: Augustus W. Corliss, 1877-1884. [family history]
      Betts, George F. "Memorial of Chancellor Erastus Cornelius Benedict." Proceedings of the Nineteenth Meeting of the University Convocation of the State of New York, held July 12-14, 1881. Albany, NY: Weed, Parsons and Company, 1883.
- Series 2: Secondary sources, 1900-2021
  - Sub-series 2.1: Articles, 1900-2021 (Box 4, Folder A-P, Box 5, Folder R-Y)
    Alexander, Arthur J., Federal Officeholders in New York State as Slaveholders 1789-1805. The Journal of Negro History 28.3, July 1943.
    Allen, Richard B., Licentious and Unbridled Proceedings: The Illegal Slave Trade to Mauritius and the Seychelles During the Early Nineteenth Century. The Journal of African History 42.1, January 2001.
    American Historical Association, AHA Council Issues Policy Resolution about Jews and the Slave Trade. Perspectives, March 1995.
    Andrews, Charles M., Colonial Commerce. The American Historical Review 20.1, October 1914.
    Anonymous, Eighteenth Century Slaves as Advertised by their Masters. The Journal of Negro History 1.2, April 1916.
    Avallone, Charlene, Catharine Sedgwick and the Circles of New York. Legacy 23.2, 2006.
    Bankoff, H. Arthur and Frederick A. Winter, The Archaeology of Slavery at the Van Cortlandt Plantation in the Bronx, New York. International Journal of Historical Archaeology 9.4, December 2005.
    Barker, Eugene C., The African Slave Trade in Texas. Southwestern Historical Quarterly 6.2, October 1902.
    BBC News, Ex-Slave Takes Niger to Court. BBC News, April 7 2008.
    Bearss, Sara B., Henry Clay and the American Claims Against Portugal, 1850. Journal of the Early Republic 7.2, Summer 1987.
    Behrendt, Stephen D., The Annual Volume and Regional Distribution of the British Slave Trade, 1780-1807. The Journal of African History 38.2, July 1997.
    Bell, Herbert C., The West India Trade Before the American Revolution. American Historical Review 22, January 1917.
    Berlin, Ira, From Creole to African: Atlantic Creoles and the Origins of African American Society in Mainland North America. The William and Mary Quarterly 53.2, April 1996.
    Block, W.T., Sabine Lake: Focal Point of the Illegal African Slave Trade. Reprinted from the Beaumont Enterprise, April 4 1974, February 5, 1984.
    Blue, A.D., Chinese Emigration and the Deck Passenger Trade. Journal of the Hong Kong Branch of the Royal Asiatic Society 10, 1970.
    Blumberg, Arnold, Diplomacy of the Mexican Empire, 1863-1867. Transactions of the American Philosophical Society 61 Part 8, 1971.
    Boardman, Helen M., First Families of Manhattan. Phylon (1940-1956) 5.2, 1944.
    Bonner, Willard Hallam, "Clamors and False Stories": The Reputation of Captain Kidd. The New England Quarterly 17.2, June 1944.
    Brookhiser, Richard, Alexander Hamilton: New Yorker. City Journal, Autumn 1996.
    Brown, Everett S., The Presidential Election of 1824-1825. Political Science Quarterly 40.3, September 1925.
    Buranelli, Vincent, The Myth of Anna Zenger. The William and Mary Quarterly 13.2, April 1956.
    Burnard, Trevor and Kenneth Morgan, The Dynamics of the Slave Market and Slave Purchasing Patterns in Jamaica, 1655-1788. The William and Mary Quarterly 58.1, January 2001.
    Burr, John E., International Repercussions of the Haitian Revolution. The Americas 26.4, April 1970.
    Cahill, Barry, The Black Loyalists Myth in Atlantic Canada. Acadiensis: Journal of the History of the Atlantic Region 29.1, Autumn 1999.
    Calhoun, Gordon, The Flagship in Africa: USS Cumberland and the Slave Trade Patrols. The Daybook: A Publication of the Hampton Roads Naval Museum 10.3, circa 2006.
    Cameron, Catherine M., How Captives Changed the World. Scientific American, December 2017.
    Capizzi, Joseph E., For What Shall We Repent? Reflections on the American Bishops, Their Teachings, and Slavery in the United States, 1839-1861. Theological Studies 65.4, December 2004.
    Carrington, Selwyn H.H., Capitalism & Slavery and Caribbean Historiography: An Evaluation. The Journal of African American History 88.3, Summer 2003.
    Chaney, Michael A., Gender Reversal and Cultural Critique in Frances Osgood's Poetry. ATQ (The American Transcendental Quarterly) 14.1, March 2000.
    Coddington, Edwin B. The Activities and Attitudes of a Confederate Business Man: Gazaway B. Lamar. The Journal of Southern History 9.1, February 1943.
    Cohen, Lucy, The Chinese of the Panama Railroad: Preliminary Notes on the Migrants of 1854 Who "Failed." Ethnohistory 18.4, Autumn 1971.
    Corbitt, Duvon C., Immigration in Cuba. The Hispanic American Historical Review 22.2, May 1942.
    Corbitt, D.C., Shipment of Slaves from the United States to Cuba, 1789-1807, pp.548-549. The Journal of Southern History 7.4, November 1941.
    Cox, James M., New England Humor: From the Revolutionary War to the Civil War. The Journal of American History 81.4, March 1995.
    Curry-Machado, How Cuba Burned with the Ghosts of British Slavery: Race, Abolition, and the Escalera. Slavery and Abolition 25.1, April 2004.
    Davis, Robert Ralph Jr., James Buchanan and the Suppression of the Slave Trade, 1858-1861. Pennsylvania History 33.4, October 1966.
    Davis, Robert Ralph Jr., Buchanian Espionage: A Report on Illegal Slave Trading in the South in 1859. The Journal of Southern History 37.2, May 1971.
    de la Cova, Antonio Rafael, Cuban Filibustering in Jacksonville in 1851. Northeast Florida History: The Journal of the Jacksonville Historical Society, 1996.
    de la Cova, Antonio Rafael, Filibusters and Freemasons: The Sworn Obligation. Journal of the Early Republic 17.1, Spring 1997.
    DeJong, Gerald Francis, The Dutch Reformed Church and Negro Slavery in Colonial America. Church History 40.4, December 1971.
    Delaney, Norman C., Raphael Semmes: The Philosophical Mariner. The Journal of Military History 62.3, July 1998.
    Desrocjers, Robert E. Jr., Slave-for-Sale Advertisements and Slavery in Massachussetts, 1704-1781. The William and Mary Quarterly 59.3, July 2002.
    Dierksheide, Christa, "The Great Improvement and Civilization of that Race": Jefferson and the "Amelioration" of Slavery, ca. 1770-1826. Early American Studies, Spring 2008.
    Dodd, Dorothy, The Schooner Emperor: An Incident of the Illegal Slave Trade in Florida. The Florida Historical Society Quarterly 13.3, January 1935.
    Drake, Frederick C. and R.W. Shufeldt, Secret History of the Slave Trade to Cuba Written By an American Naval Officer, Robert Wilson Schufeldt, 1861. The Journal of Negro History 55.3, 1970.
    Eltis, David, Free and Coerced Transatlantic Migrations: Some Comparisons. The American Historical Review 88.2, April 1983.
    Eltis, David, Senegambia and the African Slave Trade (Review). The Journal of Interdisciplanary History 30.3, Winter 1999.
    Eltis, David, The Volume and Structure of the Transatlantic Slave Trade: A Reassessment. The William and Mary Quarterly 58.1, 2001.
    Eltis, David, The U.S. Transatlantic Slave Trade, 1644-1867: An Assessment. Civil War History 54.4, 2008.
    Ely, Roland T., The Old Cuba Trade: Highlights and Case Studies of Cuban-American Interdependence during the Nineteenth Century. The Business History Review 38.4, Winter 1964.
    Fattah, Hassan M., A Nation with a Long Memory, but a Truncated History. The New York Times, January 10 2007.
    Fickling, David, Pacific islands appeal to UK for "slave voyages" compensation. The Guardian, April 13 2004.
    Fiehrer, Thomas, Saint-Dominigue/Haiti: Louisiana's Caribbean Connection. Louisiana History: The Journal of the Louisiana Historical Association 30.4, Autumn 1989.
    Finkelman, Paul, Regulating the African Slave Trade. Civil War History 54.4, 2008.
    Fitzgerald, Frances, Peculiar Instiutions: Brown University Looks at the Slave Traders in its Past. The New Yorker, September 12 2005.
    Foschio, Leslie G., A History of the Development of the Office of United States Commisioner and Magistrate Judge System. Federal Courts Law Review 4, 1999.
    Foy, Charles R., Seeking Freedom in the Atlantic World, 1713-1783. Early American Studies: An Interdisciplanary Journal 4.1, 2006.
    Franke, Katherine, Making Good on the Broken Promise of Reparations. New York Review of Books, March 2019.
    Freechling, William W., The Founding Fathers and Slavery. The American Historical Review 77.1, February 1972.
    Freudenberger, Herman and Jonathon B. Pritchett, The Domestic United States Slave Trade: New Evidence. Journal of Interdisciplinary History 21.3, Winter 1991.
    Friedman, Lee M., The First Chamber of Commerce in the United States. Bulletin of the Business Historical Society 21.5, November 1947.
    Gardiner, Clinton Harvey, Early Diplomatic Relations Between Mexico and the Far East. The Americas 6.4, April 1950.
    Geggus, David, The French Slave Trade: An Overview. The William and Mary Quarterly 58.1, January 2001.
    Gellman, David, Pirates, Sugar, Debtors, and Slaves: Political Economy and the Case for Gradual Abolition in New York. Slavery and Abolition 22.2, August 2001.
    Ghachem, Malick W., The Slave's Two Bodies: The Life of an American Legal Fiction. The William and Mary Quarterly 60.4, 2003.
    Gray, Elizabeth Kelly, "Whisper to him the word 'India'': Trans-Atlantic Critics and American Slavery, 1830-1860. Journal of the Early Republic 27, Fall 2008.
    Guyatt, Nicholas, America's Conservatory: Race, Reconstruction, and the Santo Domingo Debate. The Journal of American History, March 2011.
    Harmon, George D., The Northern Clergy and the Impending Crisis, 1830-1860. Pennsylvania Magazine of History and Biography 65, April 1941.
    Harp, Susan, Panama Railroad Heyday 1848-1869, 2001.
    Harper, Douglas, Northern Profits from Slavery. Early America Review, 2004.
    Harris, Dilue I., The Reminiscences of Mrs. Dilue Harris. Southwestern Historical Quarterly 4, 1901.
    Helfman, Tata, The Court of Vice Admiralty at Sierra Leone and the Abolition of the West African Slave Trade. Yale Law Journal 115.5, March 2006.
    Hershkowitz, Leo, Original Inventories of Early New York Jews (1682-1763). American Jewish History 90.3, September 2002.
    Hill, Lawrence F., The Abolition of the African Slave Trade to Brazil. The Hispanic American Historical Review 11.2, May 1931.
    Hirsch, Leo H., Jr., The Slave in New York. The Journal of Negro History 16.4, October 1931.
    Hoganson, Kristin, "As Badly Off as the Filipinos": U.S. Women's Suffragists and the Imperial Issue at the Turn of the Twentieth Century. Journal of Women's History 13.2, Summer 2001.
    Horton, Welsey W., The Pre-Civil War Connecticut Supreme Court. The Connecticut Law Review 34, 2002.
    Howard, Allen M., Nineteenth Century Coastal Slave Trading and the British Abolition Campaign in Sierra Leone. Slavery and Abolition 27.1, April 2006.
    Howe, Adrian, The Bayard Treason Trial: Dramatizing Anglo-Dutch Politics in Early Eighteenth Century New York City. The William and Mary Quarterly 47.1, January 1990.
    Hughes, Lynn Gordon, Richard Hildreth. Dictionary of Unitarian and Universalist Biography, circa 1999-2005.
    Ireland, Ralph R., Slavery on Long Island: A Study of Economic Motivation. Journal of Long Island History 6.2, 1966.
    Jordon, Philip D., Humor of the Backwoods, 1820-1840. The Mississippi Valley Historical Review 25.1, June 1938.
    Judd, Jacob, Brooklyn's Changing Population in the Pre-Civil War Era. Journal of Long Island History 4.2, 1964.
    Judd, Jacob, Frederick Philipse and the Madagascar Trade. New York Historical Society Quarterly 51, 1967.
    Junh, Moon-Ho, Outlawing Coolies: Race, Nation, and Empire in the Age of Emancipation. American Quarterly 57.3, 2005.
    Kelley, Sean, Blackbirders and Bozales: African-Born Slaves on the Lower Brazos River of Texas in the Nineteenth Century. Civil War History 54.4, 2008.
    Kim, Sung Bok, A New Look at the Great Landlords of Eighteenth-Century New York. The William and Mary Quarterly 27.4, October 1970.
    Klein, Herbert S., The English Slave Trade to Jamaica, 1782-1808. The Economic History Review 31.1, February 11 2008.
    Klein, Herbert S., Stanley L. Engerman, Robin Haines, and Ralph Shlomowitz, Transatlantic Mortality: The Slave Trade in Comparative Perspective. The William and Mary Quarterly 58.1, January 2001.
    Knox, Bruce, The Queen's Letter of 1865 and British Policy towards Emancipation and Indentured Labor in the West Indies, 1830-1865. The Historical Journal 29.2, June 1986.
    Landry, Harral E., Slavery and the Slave Trade in Atlantic Diplomacy, 1850-1861. The Journal of Southern History 27.2 [2 copies], May 1961.
    Lane, Calvin, The African Squadron: The U.S. Navy and the Slave Trade, 1820-1862. The Log of Mystic Seaport 50.4, 1999.
    Lebergott, Stanley. Why the South Lost: Commercial Purpose in the Confederacy 1861-1865. The Journal of American History 70.1, June 1983.
    Leisy, Ernest E., American Idiom in the Major Downing Letters, pp.78-79. American Speech 8.2, April 1933.
    Lin, Rachel Chernos, The Rhode Island Slave-Traders: Butchers, Bakers and Candlestick-Makers. Slavery and Abolition 23.3, December 2002.
    Lock, Sarah J., Legacy Bookshelf (Bibliography). Leagcy: A Journal of American Women Writers 20.1-2, January-June 2003.
    Lockett, James D., The Last Ship That Brought Slaves From Africa to America: The Landing of the Cotilde at Mobile in the Autumn of 1859. The Western Journal of Black Studies 22.3, Fall 1998.
    Lorimer, Douglas A., Black Slaves and English Liberty: A Re-examination of Racial Slavery in England. Immigrants & Minorities 3.2, 1984.
    Luis-Brown, David, An 1848 for the Americas: The Black Atlantic, "El Negro mártir," and Cuban Exile Anticolonialism in New York City. Oxford University Press, 2009.
    Lydon, James G., New York and the Slave Trade. The William and Mary Quarterly 35.2, April 1978.
    MacMaster, Richard K., ed., Long Islandiana: Negro loyalists of Long Island: unpublished petitions from the American loyalist transcripts, New York Public Library. Journal of Long Island History 4.2, 1964.
    Manz, William H., "A Just Cause for War": New York's Dred Scott Decision. NYSBA Journal, November-December 2007.
    Marsh, Richard C. The Military Trial of Gazaway Bugg Lamar. The Georgia Historical Quarterly 85.4, Winter 2001.
    Mason, Matthew, The Battle of the Slaveholding Liberators: Great Britain, the United States, and Slavery in the Early Nineteenth Century. The William and Mary Quarterly 59.3, July 2002.
    Mathis, Robert Neil. "Gazaway Bugg Lamar: A Southern Businessman and Confidant in New York City." New York History 56.3, July 1975.
    Matthews, Jean, Race, Sex, and the Dimensions of Liberty in Antebellum America. Journal of the Early Republic 6.3, Autumn 1986.
    May, Robert E., Young American Males and Filibustering in the Age of Manifest Destiny: The United States Army as a Cultural Mirror. The Journal of American History 78.3, December 1991.
    McAdams Sibley, Marilyn. James Hamilton, Jr. vs. Sam Houston: Repurcussions of the Nullification Controversy. The Southwestern Historical Quarterly 89.2, October 1985.
    McCain, William D., The Filibuster: The Career of William Walker. The Hispanic American Historical Review 18.4, November 1938.
    McGrath, Ben, Strangers on the Mountain. The New Yorker, March 1 2010.
    McKenzie, Robert Tracy, Contesting Secession: Parson Brownlow and the Rhetoric of Proslavery Unionism, 1860-1861. Civil War History 48.4, December 2002.
    McKinley, Albert E., The English and Dutch Towns of New Netherland. American Historical Review 6, October 1900.
    Menschel, David, Abolition Without Deliverance: the Law of Connecticut Slavery 1784-1848. Yale Law Journal 111, 2001.
    Middleton, Simon, "How it Came that the Bakers Bake no Bread": A Struggle for Trade Privileges in Seventeenth-Century New Amsterdam. The William and Mary Quarterly 58.2, 2001.
    Mitton, Steven Heath, The Upshur Inquiry: Lost Lessons of the Great Experiment. Slavery and Abolition 27.1, April 2006.
    Moglen, Eben, Considering Zenger: Partisan Politics and the Legal Profession in Provincial New York. Columbia Law Review, 1994.
    Moore, Rayburn S., "A Great Poet and Original Genius": Hayne Champions Poe. The Southern Literary Journal 16.1, Fall 1983.
    Morgan, Kenneth, Slave Sales in Colonial Charleston. The English Historical Review 113.453 [2 copies], September 1998.
    Morrison, Michael A., American Reaction to European Revolutions, 1848-1852 Sectionalism, Memory, and the Revolutionary Heritage. Civil War History 49.2, June 2003.
    Mosier, Joe, We Are Mere Scarecrows: USS Dale in the Africa Squadron, 1857-1859. The Day Book: A Newsletter for the Supporters of the Hampton Roads Naval Museum 4.6, September-October 1998.
    Mosier, Joe, United States v. The Bark William G. Lewis: The Navy Brings a Slave Ship to Norfolk. The Daybook: A Publication of the Hampton Roads Naval Museum 10.4, 2006.
    Mosier, Joe, Fighting Terror on the High Seas: The Navy Organizes to Fight the Real Pirates of the Caribbean. The Daybook: A Publication of the Hampton Roads Naval Museum 14.1, 2009.
    Moss, Simeon F., The Persistence of Slavery and Involuntary Servitude in a Free State (1685-1866.) The Journal of Negro History 35.3, July 1950.
    Nash, Gary B., Slaves and Slaveowners in Colonial Philadelphia. The William and Mary Quarterly 30.2, April 1973.
    Needell, Jeffrey D., The Abolition of the Brazilian Slave Trade in 1850: Historiography, slave agency and statesmenship. Journal of Latin American Studies 33.4, November 2001.
    Nickels, Cameron C., Seba Smith. Dictionary of Literary Biography, Volume 243: The American Renaissance in New England, 2001.
    Nickels, Cameron C., Seba Smith Embattled. Maine Historical Society Quarterly 13.1, Summer 1973.
    Northrup, David, Free and Unfree Labor Migration, 1600-1900: An Introduction. Journal of World History 14.2, June 2003.
    Orenstein, Jeffrey, Joseph Almeida: Portrait of a Privateer, Pirate & Plaintiff, Part I. The Green Bag 10.3, Spring 2007.
    Patterson, Cynthia, "Illustration of a Picture": Nineteenth-Century Writers and the Philadelphia Pictorials. American Periodicals 19.2, 2009.
    Pearson, Susan J., "Infantile Specimens": Showing Babies in Nineteenth-Century America. Journal of Social History, Winter 2008.
    Perkins, Howard C., The Defense of Slavery in the Northern Press on the Eve of the Civil War. The Journal of Southern History 9.4, November 1943.
    Petrulionis, Sandra Harbert, "Swelling that Great Tide of Himanity": The Concord, Massachusetts, Female Anti-Slavery Society. The New England Quarterly 74.3, September 2001.
    Pettit, Marilyn H., Slavery, Abolition, and Columbia University. Journal of Archival Organization 1.4, 2002.
    Phillips, Lawrence, British Slavery after Abolition: the Pacific Trade. Race and Class 41.3, January-March 2000.
    Pitts, Charles O Jr., Shadows on a Hillside: Robert E. Lee and Elizabeth Oakes Prince Smith, circa 1980s-1990s.
    Platt, Virginia Bever, The East India Company and the Madagascar Slave Trade. The William and Mary Quarterly 26.4, October 1969.
    Pybus, Cassandra, Jefferson's Faulty Math: The Question of Slave Defections in the American Revolution. The William and Mary Quarterly 62.2, 2005.
    Ray, Angela G., Performing Womanhood: The Lyceum Lectures of Elizabeth Oakes Smith. Society for the Study of American Women Writers Conference, November 2006.
    Ray, Angela G., What Hath She Wrought? Woman's Rights and the Nineteenth-Century Lyceum. Rhetoric and Public Affairs 9.2, 2006.
    Redway, Virginia Larkin, A New York Concert in 1736. The Musical Quarterly 22.2, April 1936.
    Reilly, Kevin S., Slavers in Disguise: American Whaling and the African Slave Trade, 1845-1862, circa 1992.
    Riddell, William Renwick, The Slave in Early New York. The Journal of Negro History 13.1, January 1928.
    Riding, Alan, Britain Confronts Legacy of Slave Trade. The New York Times, March 20 2007.
    Rink, Oliver A., The People of New Netherland: Notes on Non-English Immigration to New York and the Seventeenth Century. New York History, circa 1980.